Hey, hey, what's up, my friend?
So, I have spent years learning about
technical analysis, and I lost money.
I have learned things like trading
indicators, chart patterns, candlestick
patterns, and the more I learn, the more
confused I become.
One indicator will say buy, another
indicator will say will say sell, and
then the third indicator says, "Ask your
wife for permission first."
So, what do I do?
So, I hesitate, I overthink, and I miss
a ton of trading opportunities.
And the worst thing is I don't even know
whether what I'm doing is right or
wrong.
Despite learning so much about trading,
despite learning so much about technical
analysis.
So, if you've ever felt lost, confused,
and overwhelmed when it comes to
technical analysis, then today's
training is for you, because you will
discover number one, the truth about
technical analysis that nobody tells
you.
Two, you will learn why most traders
lose money with technical analysis, and
how you can avoid it.
And here's a clue, right? It's nothing
to do with learning more indicators or
chart patterns. Number three, how you
can use technical analysis to find
profitable trading opportunities, even
if you've tried everything else and
failed, just like me, you know, trying
to regrow my hair. And finally, I'll
teach you a complete trading system that
has generated 2,934%.
This is what I call technical analysis
backed by data. So, all this and more in
today's training. Sounds good? Then hit
the subscribe button, and let's get to
it.
To kick things off, let's first define
what is technical analysis, so we're all
on the same page. So, you don't, you
know, get confused when I talk about
this thing, and you think technical
analysis is something else altogether.
So, technical analysis is the study of
past data to help you make a trading
decision. Past data could be things like
candlestick chart, volume, etc. You're
not looking at earnings reports, you're
not reading balance sheets, or you know,
following the news. You're not trying to
figure out if a CEO is having an affair,
whether it's going to be bullish or
bearish for the stock. Instead, you're
using the chart to tell you whether to
buy or sell.
And within technical analysis, there are
a few categories, all right? So, here
are the main ones. Number one, you have
things like trading indicators.
These are mathematical formulas, all
right, overlaid on your chart. This is
where you get things like RSI, MACD,
moving averages, Bollinger Bands, and a
hundred of other things that can make
your chart look like spaghetti.
Each indicator will try to tell you
something, whether the market is
overbought, oversold, trending, or just
trying to mess with your emotions.
The next group of
technical analysis you have is chart
patterns, you know, face This is where
traders look for shapes on the charts,
you know, things like head and
shoulders, double top, triple top,
flag, pennants, etc. And for more
advanced traders, they can even look for
harmonic patterns like, you know, bat,
crab, and seafood.
And then, we also have candlestick
patterns. So, candlestick patterns, you
it's a patterns that are formed by
individual candles or a group of
candles, you know, you have names like
marubozu,
doji, harami, you know, names that sound
more like kung fu than actual trading.
At the same time, you also got other
approaches of technical analysis like
Elliott Waves, Fibonacci retracements,
volume analysis, market profile, order
flow, and the list goes on. Some of
these are simple, some are so complex
that you'll need a PhD to draw a single
line on your chart.
But here's the thing, all right? This is
important. Here's the thing.
Technical analysis analysis alone will
not
make you a profitable trader.
Let me repeat once again, because it's
important. Technical analysis alone will
not make you a profitable trader.
In fact, 95% of
who uses technical analysis, right? They
lose money. Why is that? Here are
four reasons why.
The first reason is this. Information
overload. Let me explain.
So, these days you can get access to a
ton of trading information for free, you
know, unlike the
70s or the 80s.
Just go to YouTube and one guru will
tell you to, you know, use RSI indicator
analysis. MACD is the best. And then the
third one will say, you know, forget
indicators. Naked trading is the way to
go, baby. And then you've got someone
saying, no, all three are wrong, all
right? You need to learn the secret
order flow technique based on ICT
concepts developed by the smart money
that he discovered while selling trading
courses in Bali.
And what do most traders do? Well, they
try to learn everything that they come
across, that they can get their hands
on.
You know, MACD, RSI, Fibonacci, you name
it.
They would want to learn it and try it,
thinking that
the more they learn, the better their
results is going to be.
And that's how your brain is stuffed
like a turkey on Thanksgiving, you know,
stretched, bloated, and about to kachoo
explode.
Now, the second reason why traders lose
with technical analysis is because of
conflicting signals. So, this is a
classic, right?
The RSI say that the stock is oversold.
Time to buy, baby.
But the MACD is bearish. Meanwhile, the
200-day moving average says, stay out of
the markets.
So, it's like asking three friends where
to eat for dinner. One of them says
Italian, the other one says sushi, and
the last one says,
I'm not hungry.
And if you get conflicting signals,
you will never be a confident trader
because there's always something
like an indicator that says,
this is a bad idea. Don't do it.
So, how do do make sense out of this
madness? Well, there's one technique
that I use to fix this problem and I'll
cover that in the next section.
Number three, analysis paralysis.
So, when you encounter information
overload and conflicting signals, you
will naturally get analysis paralysis.
So, this is where you sit in front of
your chart, your monitor for hours,
you're zooming in, zooming out, changing
time frames, drawing lines, erasing
lines, drawing new lines again, and by
the time you finally feel confident to
place that trade, guess what?
The move is already over.
It's like, you know, spending an hour at
the restaurant trying to decide what to
eat for dinner and before you know it,
the restaurant is closed. So, this is
what we mean by analysis paralysis. And
the fourth reason is this.
You don't know if your technical
analysis works or not. And this is the
killer one.
Most traders have never, and I repeat,
never tested whether their technical
analysis approach, whether their system
actually makes money.
Think about that.
You're risking your hard-earned money
on a strategy that you believe might
work
because some guy on the internet showed
you three cherry-picked examples.
That's like, you know, someone who won a
lottery
and then tries to teach you a strategy
so you can win the lottery like him.
But he conveniently forget to tell you
the other thousand times where he bought
a lottery ticket and didn't win anything
at all.
So, here's the deal.
In trading, you must have data to back
up your decisions.
So, you know, whether you have an edge
or not.
Otherwise, you're just gambling.
So, now let's talk about the purpose of
technical analysis. So, here's the
shift, right, that
changed my trading.
Technical analysis is not about a
trading strategy or a system. It's a set
of tools. And a tool is only useful when
you know what job it's supposed to do.
Think about it this way. A hammer is a
tool. A saw
is a tool.
A drill
is a tool. But if you use all three and
start swinging them around randomly in
your kitchen,
are you going to build a house?
Of course not.
You're going to build a mess and
probably, you know, get injured along
the way.
But if you have a blueprint, a road map,
a plan that tells you, you know, to use
the hammer over here, maybe use the
drill somewhere there, a saw for this
wooden table over here, then suddenly
these tools all have a purpose.
They serve the plan. And technical
analysis is the same.
Trading indicators, chart patterns,
candlestick patterns, they are all
tools.
But without a strategy,
a plan of how you're going to make money
from the markets, all these tools are
useless.
So, the question isn't, you know, which
indicator is the best, but rather the
real question is what's the purpose of
this tool.
And the purpose can be broken down into
one of these three categories.
Now, one of the purpose you can use
technical analysis for is to filter for
market conditions. You want to filter
for stocks according to your trading
strategy. For example, if you are using
a trend following strategy on stocks,
then you want to identify stocks which
are trending. So, this is where you can
use indicators to help you highlight,
you know, which stocks are currently in
an uptrend, for example. At the same
time, if you are, you know, let's say
trading a mean reversion strategy, you
want to identify stocks which are
currently making a pullback. Then there
are indicators for it to signal to you
certain stocks are making a pullback.
Let me walk you through a few examples
so you can see what I mean.
So, this over here, this first indicator
you are seeing over here is the 200-day
moving average. Okay, 200-day
moving average. I'm using a simple
moving average, doesn't really matter.
And the key thing is that you want to
pay attention where the price is
relative to the moving average. If the
price is above the 200-day moving
average, then you can say, "Hey, you
know, this market right now it's in a
long-term uptrend." So if you are
looking for stocks that are in an
uptrend, one tool you can use is to make
sure that the stock is trading above the
200-day moving average. And maybe for
for your
trading
markets and you're looking for markets
that are in a downtrend, maybe you like
shorting or you want to, you know,
identify stocks which are undervalued or
whatsoever, you can use, again, the
200-day moving average, but this time
around, make sure that the market is
below the 200-day moving average.
Chances are it's in a downtrend. So you
can see that you can use the moving
average indicator to help you identify,
you know, which stocks are currently in
an uptrend and which ones are in a
downtrend. And this is how moving
average can help you filter for such
market condition.
Now what about a mean reversion strategy
where you want to filter for stocks that
are currently making a pullback? So one
way to go about it is that you can use
the RSI indicator, right? The RSI, I'm
using this RSI, as you can see at the
bottom, it's a 10-period RSI. Again, the
settings isn't really too important.
What matters is the concept. And you can
see over here, this 10-day RSI right now
it's currently below 30, which signals
that, you know, the market is
temporarily over sold.
So you can see, true enough, when you
look back at the this market is
currently currently now making a
pullback. So you can see I actually used
two indicators for this chart. The first
one is this 200-day moving average,
which I shared with you earlier. So this
one tells me that, hey, you know, this
stock is in an uptrend. And then I look
at the RSI indicator, the RSI indicator,
now the 10-day RSI is below 30, it tells
me that in this uptrend the stock is now
making a pullback. So can you see how
using these different indicators can
help you, you know, filter for certain
market conditions that you're looking
for. So, these are just, you know, a few
examples to give you some idea.
So, the indicator, right, isn't telling
you what exactly to buy or sell. No,
it's not trying to do that. It's telling
you whether the market conditions are
suitable for your strategy. So, for
example, let's say you're looking for
stocks which are in an in an uptrend.
And if the price is below the 200-day
moving average, so it immediately tells
you that isn't a stock you want to be
looking for. So, that's how the filter
works. It's like, you know, checking the
weather before you go for a picnic. You
want to make sure that the weather
conditions are favorable before you
leave your house for the picnic. Does
that make sense? Now, the second purpose
you can use technical analysis for is to
help you define your entry trigger. So,
this means when exactly to enter a trade
once you have, you know, filtered the
market according according to your
strategy. Okay? So, entry trigger, there
are many ways to go about it, but here
are a few ideas for you. So, let's say
for example, you are
adopting a trend-following strategy.
Okay, so trend-following meaning that
you want to, you know, buy stocks in an
uptrend and then you want to ride it for
as long as it lasts. So, you can see
over here, stock above the 200-day
moving average, we can conclude that
this stock is in a long-term uptrend.
What about entry trigger? It could be as
something as simple like a breakout. So,
over here I've overlaid with a Donchian
Channel breakout.
d o n c h i n
Donchian Channel breakout. I've changed
it to uh the settings to 50. So,
we're looking for a breakout over the
last 50 days. So, what happens is that
if the price
touches this upper blue line,
okay, this upper blue line, it means
that the price has made a new 50-day
high. And that's a signal as an entry
trigger to go long on that 50-day
breakout.
So, that's one way you can use the
Donchian Channel as an entry trigger to
go long, right? You don't have to guess,
wonder what if, you know, is there Do I
need any more confirmation? No, the
Donchian Channel can serve as an entry
trigger to enter on a breakout.
Next one, for those of you who are more
of, you know, trading pullbacks and
whatnot,
you can see over here, again, we have a
the first indicator shown over here, the
moving average. Stock is above The stock
is above it, so it's in a long-term
uptrend.
The RSI, you can see right now is below
30, so it's making a pullback as what
you see over here. So, now, when exactly
do you enter a trade? So, for mean
reversion, there are a few ways you can
go about it depending on whether you
want to adopt a systems trading approach
approach or more of a discretionary
approach. So, for systems trader,
when they adopt a mean reversion trading
approach, when they have, you know,
stock which is in an uptrend and is
temporarily oversold because the 10-day
RSI is below 30, what they can do is
just simply place a buy limit order. So,
in this case, let's say, for example,
you place a buy limit order,
let's say at $255,
somewhere over here, a buy limit. Okay?
This over here is the buy limit.
Buy limit order. So, next day, if the
market
continues down trading lower and it hits
our buy limit order, we will get long.
Right? So, the buy limit order is our
entry trigger. We are
wanting to see if the market can, you
know, stretch further to hit our buy
limit order to get us filled on the
trade. So, that's one way of entering a
mean reversion strategy.
Uh later on, I'll go into more details.
Another way, for those of you who are
more of a
trading discretionary, right? You can
use tools like candlestick patterns.
Some of
the traders like to look for things like
a bullish hammer, okay? Looking for a
reversal. And if that happens, then you
go long on the next day open. That's
another way you can uh use an entry
trigger to help you time your entry.
Some could maybe use things like a RSI.
If the RSI crosses back above 30, in
this case, if the RSI crosses back above
30, right? That could be a signal to go
long as well. So, there are different
ways to use that entry trigger to to go
long.
And what One thing they all have in
common is this, that they are objective,
they are specific.
And there's no room for, you know, I
think or I feel because once you have
that, right? Then you're just going to
introduce a lot of a subjectivity, a lot
of emotions and gut feeling into your
trading, and it leads to inconsistent
results. So, when you stop treating your
entry like a subjective art form and
start treating it like a specific
trading rule to know exactly what you're
looking for, your results will start
changing because your action starts
becoming a lot more consistent. And when
your actions are consistent, you get
consistent results. Okay, it's like the
difference between saying, you know,
"I'll go to the gym when I feel like
it." versus "I'll go to the gym at 7:00
a.m. every Monday, Wednesday, and
Friday." You see the difference? And
finally, you must know when to exit your
trade. And when you know when to exit,
so it all again all boils down to the
strategy that you're employing. Whether
are you looking to ride a trend? Are you
looking to capture a swing like a mean
reversion system? So, it all boils down
to your strategy or your goals, okay?
So, let me give you a few examples. So,
for example, a trend-following strategy,
you look to ride the trend till it ends.
So, this is where you know your
technical analysis tools must be
something that allows you to ride the
trend.
And at the same time, if you are going
with a mean reversion strategy,
otherwise
some traders, you know, call it swing
trading, looking to capture one swing,
capture one bounce. You want to use a
tool, an indicator, that tells you when
to exit, right? When the market has made
a bounce. So, let me give you a couple
of ideas.
So, over here, again, if you recall,
this blue indicator on the chart is the
Don- Donchian Channel. So, let's say for
whatever reason, let's say maybe
you managed to go long uh somewhere over
here on this breakout. You went long and
you're riding the trend and you're
wondering, you know, when to exit, when
is the trend over? So, one way you can
go about it is that you can use again
the Donchian Channel and exit, right,
only when the price breaks and close
below the Donchian Channel, meaning
hitting the low. So, this tells you when
the price closes below the 50-day
low, this is where you exit the trade
and take your profit. So, in this case,
it's going to be around a break-even
trade or maybe just a very small loss.
And it happens, right, very typical for
a trend-following system. And where I
think some traders might be wondering
that is, you know, "Rayner, if you look
at this, man, Rayner, this isn't a good
time to exit this position. Look, you're
selling, yeah, you're exiting into
support.
I agree. This is an area of support and
if you exit this trade, you might be,
you know,
cutting your position into an area of
support.
But the question is this,
what is
the purpose? What is your strategy? What
is your goal?
And if you think back, the goal of this
strategy, of this system, this trend
following system is to ride the trend.
And right now, the trend is showing
signs of reversal and your exit signal
is a close below the 50-day moving
average. So, why do you care if you're
cutting into support?
Why do you care? Because it has no
relevance to your strategy. It has no
relevance to your goal. So, this is the
importance of knowing
what is the strategy you're trading and
then using the right tools to meet the
strategy. Because if you don't, then
this is what's going to happen, right?
You're going to get analysis paralysis,
conflicting information. But when you
know your strategy, you know what is
your purpose, you know the goal, all
this is what we call the noise and you
can easily tune it out and you don't
feel conflicted anymore. So, this is
just one example of
of uh how traders tend to overcomplicate
things. They doubt themselves because
all these different tools and indicators
are giving them conflicting information.
And the way to fix it is to know what is
the strategy you're trading.
What are the
tools that you're going to use
to meet the purpose of the strategy. And
in this case, let's say a trend
following strategy, the purpose is to
ride the trend. What tools can you use
to meet that purpose? So, this is
important, right?
Rewatch this segment right here if you
need further clarity, especially for
those of you who always, you know, get
conflicting information, analysis
paralysis, etc.
Okay, another example over here. So,
let's say in this case, instead of a
trend following strategy, you adopt a
mean reversion strategy and you're
looking to exit on the bounce. Let's
say, for example, you managed to get an
entry somewhere over here. Maybe, you
know, there's this price rejection, you
go long or, you know, you place a buy
limit order, you got filled, right?
Because
because uh the next day the price did
trade down lower over here. So, what
whatever the case, whether you use a
limit order, whether you wait for a
candlestick pattern reversal, or the RSI
is above 30, whatever, let's say you got
long. When do you exit the trade? So,
one way you can go about it is that you
can you can exit when the RSI again
crosses above a certain threshold. So,
in this case, let's say the RSI has now
crossed above 50. Let's say we use 50 as
our threshold.
Okay? If the RSI crosses above 50, right
now it's 51, this is our signal to exit
the trade. So, in this case, you can see
that you have caught uh this uh nice
bounce higher. So, there are many
different indicators and tools that you
can use to meet all these uh different
uh requirements of your strategy. The
purpose I'm sharing this over here is to
kind of like show you how the concept
works.
As you can see,
different strategies, they have
different objectives, and you must use
the different tools to meet these
objectives. Does it make sense?
Smash the thumbs up button, right, if it
if you makes sense to you. Okay, let's
do a quick recap, shall we, before
we move on into the trading system that
has generated 2,934%.
So, first thing is that technical
analysis,
it must have a purpose. The reason why
you feel technical analysis is
overwhelming, confused, and you feel
conflicted is because you do not know
what purpose it serves. So, in this
training today, I explained to you
technical analysis can serve three broad
purposes. Number one, to filter for
market conditions. Number two, to help
you define your entry trigger to know
when exactly to enter a trade. And
number three, to tell you when to get
out of the trade. And as you can see,
right, filtering for market conditions,
and possibly even your exits, and even
your entry, yeah. It all depends on the
type of trading strategy that you want
to employ. If you're going with the
trend following strategy, then you
typically filter for stocks in an
uptrend, your exit would usually have a
trailing stop loss. If you are going
with a mean reversion strategy, you
typically would capture one swing, and
your exit usually won't be looking to
ride the trend, but looking to sell on
the first bounce or the first wave
higher. So,
again, you must know the purpose of your
technical analysis
and
knowing the purpose of your technical
analysis, right, depends on the type of
trading strategy that you are employing.
Next one, every tool on your chart must
have a purpose. So, if there's a line,
there's an indicator, there's a pattern
on your chart that you have no idea what
it's there for be- besides, you know,
making your chart looks good, remove
that stupid line, okay? Because it's
only going to confuse you, it's going to
make you feel conflicted, and you
probably will get analysis paralysis
when you have so many things down there
on your chart and you're not even sure
what's the purpose of it. So, less is
more. Remove the stuff that, you know,
you realize that you don't even know
what it's there for in the first place.
Next one, one purpose, one tool. Right,
this is how you're going to declutter
and trade with clarity. So, for example,
let's say you are looking to identify
stocks
that are making a pullback.
If you want to go with the RSI indicator
as what I've shared with you earlier,
fair enough, go ahead. But, don't put
the RSI, the CCI, the MACD, and no and
no and no whatever I I I because when
you have so many indicators to help you
define a pullback, you're going to end
up feeling confused, overwhelmed, and
sometimes even get conflicting signals,
especially when your different
indicators have different settings. So,
just use one indicator, for example, to
define a pullback, good enough. Use one
indicator to help you define a trend,
that's good enough.
Having more such indicators doesn't mean
that your trading results will improve.
I think far from it. More often than
not, you add more stuff,
your results will get worse. And you
probably get confused and, you know,
uh panic. Ah, what should I do now?
Okay? And finally,
you won't know whether your technical
analysis works until you test it. So,
this is important, right?
The only way to know whether a strategy
or system works is you must back test
it. You must test it across, let's say,
over the last 10 years, 20 years, and
see how it has performed. And same thing
for technical analysis, your technical
analysis is to help you
serve a purpose, right? Whether to
define your entry trigger, to filter for
market conditions, etc. How do you know
whether it works or not? You don't until
you test it. So, this is why it's
important to test
the strategy, to test the system that
you've developed. So, this will give you
the confidence to trade it in the live
markets. And that's why right now I'm
going to teach you a complete trading
system
using the concepts I've shared with you.
This is what I call a technical
technical technical analysis backed by
data. And this system has generated
2,934%
over the last 25 years. Interested? Then
let's get to it.
Now, this is a mean reversion trading
system that we'll be trading in the US
stock market. So, to give you an idea
what it looks like, the idea behind it,
we're looking for stocks that are in an
uptrend.
Waiting for it to make a pullback. When
it makes a pullback, we're looking to
buy.
And then when it makes a bounce higher,
boing,
we're going to sell. And then thereby
capturing capturing this one bounce,
this one swing in the stock market. So,
these are the exact trading rules over
here. First thing we'll be trading
stocks in the Russell 1000. These are
the 1000 largest stocks in the US. Our
risk management is 10% capital and
maximum of 10 stocks. So, very simple.
If you have a $100,000, this means we
can buy a maximum of 10 stocks and each
stock we will allocate $10,000 to each
stock. So, this is the risk management
and position sizing. Time frame it will
be on the daily time frame. Now, let's
look at the exact trading rules.
And I'll explain to you the
concept behind it. Number one, the stock
is above the 200-day average. What is
this for? This technical analysis to
help us define stocks which are in an
uptrend. This is the filter.
Next one, the stock made a 15-day low.
This is also a filter, a filter to help
us
narrow down stocks which are currently
making a pullback.
Number three, entry trigger. Very simple
stuff. Place a 2% buy limit order based
on the previous day's closing price. And
finally, number four, if your order is
filled, sell the stock.
Sell Sell when the stock closes higher
or after 10 trading days. This is the
exit signal. And if somehow you have
you know, in the bull market we have too
many trading opportunities to choose
from. We typically want to choose uh
stocks that have increased the most in
price over the last 100 days. So,
the ranking is ROC 100, right? We will
favor stocks that have increased the
most in price over the last 100 days,
especially if we have too many trading
opportunities to select from.
So,
with these rules, let me show you how it
looks like on the chart.
So, if we look at this one over here,
clearly this is a cherry-pick example
just to illustrate my point.
The stock you can see over here is above
the 200-day moving average. So, we can
say that, "Hey, you know, this stock is
right now in an uptrend. It meets our
criteria." Next one,
the RSI. Oh, no, no, not using RSI,
sorry. In this case, we're using the
15-day low. So, how do you know whether
right now the stock price has made a
15-day low? So, on this candle, ask
yourself,
"Based on this closing price, is this
the lowest closing price over the last
15 days?" So, you can count it manually
if you want. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12
13 14 15. So, you can see that over the
last 15 days from here
all the way to here, this is
the lowest closing price over the last
15 days. So, that meet our requirement.
That is how we define a pullback. So,
you can see there many ways to define a
pullback. Can use RSI, CCI, can use, you
know,
typical
markets, you know, closing X day low,
that is fine as well. So, what we're
going to do now is we're going to place
a buy limit order, just 2% buy limit
order based on the previous day closing
price. So, it's going to be I've done
the math, 15.87. So, let's say we get
our indicator out. Oh, sorry. I mean
just this horizontal line. I put it
here. Let's put it green.
Okay.
And let's say that this one is at 15.87.
15.87. That is our buy limit order. So,
this means if the next day the price
touches this green line, it means we are
long. We are filled on the trade. Okay,
let's see what happens. In this case,
boom. The market did trade into our buy
limit order and now we are long. So now,
what about our exit? So, if you recall,
our exit is very straightforward.
We exit the trade when the stock closes
higher,
meaning your green candle. If it forms a
green candle, it means that we're going
to sell or after 10 trading days. So,
this one is a time-based exit. Just in
case sometimes, you know, the stock
didn't make a higher close, it just go
down day after day.
No rally, no bounce at all. This is
where we will use the time-based exit to
exit our trade. So, in this case, you
can see again, as mentioned, this is a
cherry-picked example. Boom, right? The
stock closed higher for the day, right?
And we're going to exit the trade
the next day. Yeah, so this is a will
clearly be a a winning trade. And again,
you I don't want you to take what I say
at face value. In fact, go and do the
testing and verify for yourself and see
how this has worked how this performed,
right? Over the last 10, 20 years. And
this is actually what I have done. So,
let me just share with you the back test
results, right? Of this trading system.
Now, this is the back test results and
as you can see over here, this system
Okay, I'll just show you the equity
curve first.
So, you can see this green line over
here is the performance of this trading
system over the last 20, 25, 26 years
compared to the S&P 500, which is this
blue line over here. You can see that it
has a outperformed the market. Yeah, it
has beaten the market over the last two
over decades, two plus decades.
Annual return
in the long run is about 14%. Your
maximum drawdown over here it's about
37% compared to the S&P. I think the S&P
drawdown is much higher, 55, 60%. Your
winning rate is about 60% for this
particular trading system as well. Okay?
So,
uh over here I've I've pulled up the
data here. So, you can see this are all
the the metrics for this particular
trading system.
So, one thing to be aware of is
this trading system it typically does
well when the markets are in a range or
it's choppy. But in a bear market, this
system will
likely underperform because most of
these stocks will reverse. So, you buy
the pullback, you know, what's cheap is
going to become cheaper. So, that's
where you will experience a drawdown
during a bear market.
And this brings me to my next point on
how do you then
profit
almost every single year regardless of
market conditions. Whether it's a bull
market, whether it's a bear market,
whether it's during a recession, you
have a very high probability of, you
know, making profit in a given year. So,
this is where I need to introduce to you
the concept of multiple trading systems.
Because when you combine multiple
trading systems, this is where is what,
you know, I call the holy grail of
trading. This is what allows you to be
in the top 1% of traders. Let me give
you an analogy. Let's say you open a
restaurant. Maybe it's a Chinese
restaurant. And let's say for the given
year, maybe you don't have any Chinese
tourists or Chinese people just somehow
feel like eating Chinese food. Nobody
wants to eat Chinese food that year. I'm
Chinese, by the way.
What's going to happen to your
restaurant? Well, that year, you know,
your restaurant the revenue is going to
drop. If that's the only restaurant you
have, your income is going to
collapse as well. Agree?
But at the same time, what if you have
five restaurants? And each restaurant
sells different cuisine, Italian,
Japanese, uh Mediterranean, etc. And all
these five restaurants are in five
different locations.
Now, what if in a given year, one of
these restaurant doesn't perform?
Does it matter?
Well, it matters, but will it affect
your
livelihood? Probably not, right? Because
you have four other restaurants which
will be doing okay, and that is more
than enough to cover the losses of that
one restaurant. Yeah? So, it's the same
thing for trading. When you have one
trading systems versus multiple trading
systems, you will increase the odds,
right, of making a profit in a given
year because you have
profits from other trading system that
could cushion the loss of a specific
trading system that isn't doing well in
a given year. So, let me give you an
example.
So, over here you're seeing is, you
know, two different trading systems that
I teach in the ultimate systems trader
program. So, you can see the first
system is called STF. It's a trend
following system and it has losing
years. 2009 lost money, 2012 it lost
money, 2018 lost money, 2023, 2024. Same
thing for this one over here. MRT is not
the choo-choo train in Singapore. It's a
mean reversion trading system. You can
see that in 2014 it lost money here,
lost money here as well.
On its own, right, these trading systems
they have losing years. But, when you
combine them, right, let's say if you
have, you know, $100,000 capital, you
put 50% to this trend following, 50% to
mean reversion trading, then you look at
this last column. Notice how
your losing years is dramatically
reduced. Only one losing years, which
which is in 2023, a loss of 5%. You've
made money in the dot-com bubble, you've
made money in the 2008 financial crisis,
you've made money in the COVID,
Russia-Ukraine war. All these different
difficult market conditions, you are
also profitable. And that's the power of
having multiple trading systems, right,
that are working for you. Now, covering
all these different trading systems is
not within the scope of today's video.
Today is more of
helping you understand
what technical analysis can do for you,
to understand the purpose behind it. So,
if you want to learn more about such
different trading systems, you can go
and grab my free training over here. In
this 54-minute free training, I will
teach you three specific trading
systems. One is a mean reversion trading
system, one is a trend following system,
and then I will teach you a momentum
trading system. So, that when you
combine all these different multiple
trading systems, it dramatically
increase your odds
of making a profit in a given year,
regardless of market conditions. And
I'll give you the exact trading rules,
same as what I've done earlier in this
video. I'll give you chart examples,
trading cheat sheets, and whatnot, so
you can understand these trading systems
inside out. So, no fluff, right? It's
all practical theory and real-world
actionable stuff that you can apply.
So, yeah, you also get the PDF slide of
the training, the trading cheat sheets,
and backtest reports of all these
different systems. So, if you're
interested, just go down to my website
over here, tradingwithrayner.com/go,
or you can, you know, scan this QR code
and get access to this free training.
So, with that said,
I'll also put the link somewhere below
this video if it's easier for you to
click. So, with that said, I wish you
good luck, good trading, have a great
year ahead, have a great day ahead, and
I will talk to you soon.